======================================================================
CS2110                          Lab #4                       Fall 2010
======================================================================

This is not a timed lab, so feel free to collaborate with your neighbors, use
the book, and ask the TAs for explanation if you need help. When you are done,
please submit your assignment to T-Square to get "credit" for participating.

-------------------
Part 1: Transistors
-------------------
Transistors are like tiny electrical switches. Logic gates (like AND gates,
OR gates, etc.) are composed of transistors in much the same way that the
functional units you will build later are composed of logic gates. There are
2 types of MOS (metal-oxide semiconductors) transistors.

Your job is to now build the following logic gates!

Build a or gate.

Note: Please follow the convention that your p-type gates are at the top of your circuit..

Beware! if your output wire of your gates is a blue or red wire then your circuit is not correct

B) Look at the image mystery.png what basic logic gate is this.  Can you give me a truth table for it?
		
XOR   
0 | 0 | 0
0 | 1 | 1
1 | 0 | 1
1 | 1 | 0


======================================
Part 2: Decoders/Encoders/Multiplexors
======================================

a) Make a two-input decoder.
   * How many outputs does this decoder have? 4
   * What is the relationship between the number of inputs and the number of outputs of a decoder? 2^inputs = outputs

b) Make a two-output encoder.
   * How many inputs does this encoder have? 4
   * What is the relationship between the number of inputs and the number of outputs? 
   * What can break an encoder? Entering a value that can't be encoded
   * Does a decoder have this problem? No

c) Make a mux with two select lines.
   * How many inputs does this mux have? 8
   * How many outputs does this mux have? 1
   * What is the relationship between the number of inputs and select lines for a mux? 2^n inputs = n select lines

Create all of these circuits in a file named lab4Part2.circ

------------
Deliverables
------------

This file named lab4.txt
lab4Part1.circ
lab4Part2.circ